if you don't know the head and shoulders
pattern then you won't know how it made
be $7,000 in this trade alone in
literally 45 hours now if you don't
understand it it's okay don't worry
about it in this video I'm going to
explain to you everything you need to
know in order for you to understand how
to use the head and shoulders pattern
and how you can benefit from it and I'm
going to show you how this has
personally made me anywhere from $50 to
$100,000 in one single day by simply
understanding how to use this pattern in
the middle of the chart or at the bottom
or the high it's going to indicate to
you whether it's a good time to buy or
to sell so in this video I'm going to
show you how you can identify it and how
you can leverage it to make money in the
markets every single day how I do it so
first things first in order for you to
understand how this pattern works I have
to give you some context you understand
what it is so how does the head and
shoulders pattern actually work so the
head and shoulders pattern is actually a
full reversal pattern there's
continuation patterns and there is
reversal pattern The Head and Shoulders
is a complete reversal pattern where you
would be going against the trend of the
market where it's going in that
direction let me explain a normal Head
and Shoulders is something that you
would see at a top of a market it's very
simple to identify because you would see
a left a head and then a right shoulder
it almost looks like three triangles you
have two little ones which are the
shoulders and then you have one big one
which is the head this is what it's
called a head and shoulders so now you
usually have this head and shoulders at
the high of a market whether it's been
going bullish for a long period of time
or you've hit a very strong level of
resistance now once you get this head
and shoulder pattern and after it breaks
the neckline that is when it is
confirmed that now this Market is going
to completely reverse now this is going
to make more sense when we get into the
charts in just a second and then an
inverted Head and Shoulders is literally
the same exact thing but just inverted
it's where you have a head and shoulders
but at the bottom of a market so this is
a bearish market that has been going
bearish for a very long time or a
significant amount of time or we have
reached a strong level of support and
then we have formed the inverted Head
and Shoulders now indicating to us that
now this Market is going to shift start
going to the upside so remember the head
and shoulders pattern is the complete
opposite of a continuation pattern this
is a pattern that is only meant for
reversal usually happens at a high or at
a resistance or at a low or at a strong
level of support showing us that the
market is going to completely reverse so
now that you understand what the actual
Head and Shoulders means I'm going to
actually show you what it looks like on
the market now keep in mind Head and
Shoulders happen on all different time
frames at different times and some of
them can be prettier than others others
can be a little bit harder to spot and
others can be extremely obvious but they
all have the same effect because what
matters is the way the market shifts and
structure but all this is going to make
sense right now so as you guys can see
right here this is a very clear
indication of a head and shoulders
happening at a high in the market as you
can see right here this is a left
triangle right here this is the bigger
triangle right here and then this is the
other triangle this is also known as the
left shoulder this is known as the head
and then this is known as the right
shoulder there's actually a tool on
trading view that is called The Head and
Shoulders pattern you can find it right
here in this section called head and
shoulders and you can throw this from
the bottom here put it at the left
shoulder then you raise it up to the
head and then you drop it back down and
you can see how you have a beautiful
head and shoulders pattern this is where
you can consider a valid and correct
Head and Shoulders now this happens the
same as a inverted Head and Shoulders it
is literally the complete opposite so to
keep it very simple I can just flip the
chart and you can see how now this right
here is an inverted Head and Shoulders
you have the left you have the head and
then you have the right shoulder you can
see how the market completely shifted
and continue headed in the opposite
direction of the market and these happen
literally in every single time frame all
throughout the charts we have to be very
selective on picking the right head and
shoulders because they could be a little
misleading I probably wondering how does
this head and shoulders work does it
just happen randomly in the chart the
answer is yes but it's not effective so
I'm going to be showing you right now
how this actually spot up a head and
shoulders at a strong level of support
or resistance so then you can take
advantage of it this is where you
actually want to be entering the trade
off of the head and shoulders so as you
guys can see right here there's actually
multiple head and shoulders in this
market right here but we're going to
spot one example so if you guys want try
and pause the video for a second and see
if you could spot The Head and Shoulders
whether it's a regular Head and
Shoulders or an inverted head and
shoulders so this right here there's
actually a beautiful inverted Head and
Shoulders that is rejecting off of this
level of support right here as you can
see this is creating a
left head and then this right here would
be our right shoulder you can mark this
as your right shoulder you could also
include this as your right shoulder what
matters is that you're getting the
triangles and you're getting the shift
of structure where now price is going to
then reverse and most importantly you
are rejecting a strong level of support
if you notice after that happens then
you have the break the retest of the
neckline and then the complete reversal
in the market these Head and Shoulders
you only want to take them at a strong
level of support as an inverted Head and
Shoulders or you want to take them at a
strong resistance level as a regular
head and shoulders so as you can tell
this Market was heading to the downside
and then we reached the level of support
we created the head and shoulders and
now it's the complete reversal pattern
that makes this market now shift to the
upside so if you see it like this you
can see how this right here is the head
and shoulders pattern and how the market
has now shifted this is literally the
same exact price that you're seeing
right here but in a line form chart
right here so now you're probably
wondering where do you enter the trade
on the head and shoulders and there's
actually couple areas where you can
enter it depending if you want to have a
high risk trade or you want to have a
conservative risk trade and if you want
to know what is the difference between a
high risk trade or a low risk trade
click this video right here where I
literally explain to you the right risk
management that you should have on your
personal account funded account or when
you get started in trading because Head
and Shoulders is very key into trading
and if you use the right risk the right
way you can make a lot of money in
trading so make sure you check that
video out but in this trade right here
for example you could have had three
different entries on this trade so we
can have the highrisk trade first so
before we get into that we have to
explain what is a head and shoulders
entry so as you can tell as of right now
this right here is not a head and
shoulders because as of right now this
can simply create a new lower low in the
market and this there's no head and
shoulders the only way you get uh Head
and Shoulders is once you get this
structure point to break above the last
structure point and then the right
shoulder is once it starts having a
rejection from the equal left shoulder
Zone want to make sure that the
shoulders match up more or less at the
same area they cannot be always
perfectly the same so you know give it
some Breathing Room you know it doesn't
matter if this one's a little bit higher
or it's a little bit lower because
obviously the markets are going to
change so give it a little bit of the
breathing room but they kind of have to
be more or less within the same Zone but
the key Point here is that this
structure Point has closed above that
structure point because if you notice
look at the neckline the neckline is
this dotted line as you can see if it is
under that structure point that line is
still facing to the downside and
remember this is a reversal pattern so
you want to have the most indications
you can that this is now going to
reverse and as of right now this is not
a strong indication that it has reversed
once this has broken above the structure
point you can see how now this line has
now shifted to heading to the upside and
you can see how it goes to the upside
for the long term so you want to make
sure that when you're marking off your
head and shoulders this line of the
neckline is always heading up if it's an
inverted head and shoulders and if it's
a normal Head and Shoulders you want to
make sure that it is heading to the
downside so for example this right here
would not be a valid head and shoulders
because this is still heading to the
upside a regular Head and Shoulders is a
reversal pattern meaning it's going to
now head to the downside so you want to
make sure that the neckline is under
this structure Point indicating to us
that now we're heading to the downside
so now that you know that the neck line
is heading to the downside where do you
enter the highrisk trade that's where a
lot of people want to know and it's very
simple it's at the potential right
shoulder and why do I say potential well
because there's nothing confirmed yet
that this is a right shoulder for all we
know this can have a pull back to here
and then this have a then push to the
upside and it's a fake Head and
Shoulders which happens all the time in
the market that's why this is considered
a high-risk trade because it's still not
yet confirmed as a head and shoulders or
inverted head and shoulders so you would
be taking the trade at the potential
right shoulder once you have a rejection
section Candlestick you would enter your
trade right around here and your stop
loss would either be right above the
head or a little bit above the right
shoulder and this is a very highrisk
trade but it has a lot of reward with it
because if you get this trade right not
only do you completely catch the right
shoulder but then you can scale in once
you enter on the retest of the neckline
to then head to the downside which is
the actual trade you should be entering
once you have a head and shoulders so
this is a highrisk trade which is
entering at the potential right shoulder
and then the actual trade is entering at
the retest of the neckline of the head
and shoulders so this is the same exact
thing but on a reversal pattern to head
to the upside you would be entering the
trade at the potential right shoulder
stoploss can be above the head or right
around the shoulder and then you are
predicting for the shoulder to
completely form here but the actual
trade that you should be taking is at
the retest of the neckline of the The
Head and Shoulders where this is where
you either scale into a trade or
actually get into your first position on
the head and shoulders so if I literally
take this same exact example that I just
showed it to you into this trade right
here you guys can see how the actual
Head and Shoulders if you mark it off
right here if this were to be the right
shoulder this is not the ideal right
shoulder why because the neckline is
still heading to the downside so that is
why this right here would be the ideal
neckline because now you see how it's
shifting to the upside so this elbow
would go right here and then your first
highrisk trade would be taking at the
equal right shoulder if you notice it is
basically the equal to this point right
here just to get a little bit more
clarity I could bring it up and you can
see how this is exactly how it looks so
you're taking it approximately at the
equal of the left shoulder so this could
be one entry right here and if you
notice you have your bullish engulfing
Candlestick your morning star formation
retest of structure all of this stuff
that I talk about all the time I also
explain in this video right here which
it explains it to Perfection so now that
you enter at that point right there that
could be your highrisk trade but let's
say you don't want to enter the trade on
the high-risk trade which is perfectly
fine you want to enter at the break and
retest of the neckline by all means and
that is exactly where this trade right
here comes in you have a break and then
a retest of the next line of the head
and shoulders and the same exact bullish
engulfing Morning Star confirmation you
get it right here and then this would be
the ideal entry signal so you have the
actual trade you should be taking which
is the retest of The Head and Shoulders
which is the normal risk trade and then
you have the higher risk trade which is
going to be the right shoulder retesting
the left shoulder area of Interest now
with this pattern you're going to see it
everywhere in the markets the 1 hour the
4 Hour the daily the weekly all of these
time frames obviously the higher the
time frame the more respected it's going
to be and with this pattern alone it's
going to be plenty to make money in the
markets if used correctly with a trading
plan and when the students incorporate
this pattern with my trading plan they
make anywhere from ,000 to
$1,500 a week using my set and forgest
strategy you're probably wondering what
is a set and forgest strategy just click
the link in the description below I have
a video there for you that explains
absolutely exactly what it means
students are making anywhere from $1,000
to $11,500 a week in their first 3
months as a beginner set in foret Trader
where I incorporate these patterns along
with my trading plan to have an edge
over the market to make anywhere from a
,000 to $1,500 a week as a beginner set
up foret trade you want to know more
about it just click the link in the
description below I have a video there
for you that explains everything to
Perfection with that being said I hope
this video is very useful to you guys
and you can guys now make money using
the head and shoulders pattern just make
sure you have a key trading plan to now
Excel and take you guys to the next
level appreciate you guys watching the
video all the way to the end I'll see
you guys in the next video